Guide to the Great Northern Railway Company (U.S.) Timetables, Tariffs, Route Maps and Other Printed Ephemera
Department of Special Collections
Great Northern Railway Company (U.S.) Timetables, Tariffs, Route Maps and Other Printed Ephemera
1890-1950
M1321
Great Northern Railway Company (U.S.)
1.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Timetables, tariffs, route maps and other printed ephemera, ca. 1890-1950.
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
Direct source of acquisition unknown. Believed to have been part of the Mark Hopkins Transportation Collection.
Scope and Content of Collection
Timetables, tariffs, route maps and other printed ephemera, ca. 1890-1950.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Great Northern Railway Company (U.S.); Railroads--United States--History.; Transportation--History.; Glacier National Park (Mont.)
Collection Contents
- History, 1895 - 1962, Series 1
  - The Great Northern Bulletin1895 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Great Northern Country1896 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    James J. Hill
  - Great Northern Bulletin1898 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Minnesota
  - New Extensions of the Great Northern Railway[1904 ?] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "The Autobiography of an Engine"1909 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Al Smith [engineer]
  - "Dedication and Opening of the New Cascade Tunnel"1929 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Ralph Budd; J. B. Campbell; W. W. Atterbury; Herbert Hoover; Roland H. Hartley; James F. Stevens
  - New Cascade Tunnel--Radio Broadcast Program1929 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Railway and Marine News"[1929 ?] (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Frederick Mears; "Conquering the Cascades"
  - "The Unseen Service"[1920s ?] (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Commissary
  - "Rail Fact and Fiction," speech by Thomas Balmer1944, Sep. 29 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Balmer, Thomas
  - Condensed History, Great Northern Railway1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Trains, ca. 1900 - 1952, Series 2
  - "See America First Trains" [1900s ?] (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 'Some New Features on the Oriental Limited" [1900s ?] (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "A Quartette of Fast Trains" 1904 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Changes in Time and Train Service" [1900s ?] (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "From the Car Window" 1925 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Empire Builder" [1930s ?] (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "The Empire Builder, Great Northern's Finest Transcontinental Train"[1930s ?] (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Empire Builder--Luxury Coaches" [1930s] (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "Empire Builder--Private Bedrooms." [1930s ?] (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Empire Builder--Airconditioning" [1930s ?] (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "Empire Builder" [1933?] (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "Through Your Car Window" (Streamlined Empire Builder)1949, May (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "Good Morning--Here You Are !" (Route Guide, Empire Builder)1950, Apr. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "Mid-Century Empire Builder"1951, May (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Through Your Car Window." (Streamlined Empire Builder)1952, Apr. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Maps, 1927 - 193?, Series 3
  - Route Maps, Great Northern Railway (2)1927 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Route Maps, Great Northern Railway1935 & 1936 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Great Northern Map of the United States1948 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Pictorial Map, Glacier National Park[1920s ?] (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Pictorial Map, Glacier National Park1939 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Pictorial Map, Glacier National Park1948 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Aeroplane Map, Glacier / Waterton Lakes National Parks (2)[1920s ?] (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Aeroplane Map, Glacier National Park (2)[1920s ?] (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Aeroplane Map, Glacier National Park (2)[1930s ?] (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Tariffs, 1933 - 1947, n.d., Series 4
  - "On Your Next Trip", 1933 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Tariff of Charges, Glacier National Park and Waterton Lakes Park1936 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Winter Fares East1936 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - "Eastern Trips For Western People" 1936 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - "Low Coach Fares"[1930s ?] (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Rates, Glacier and Waterton National Parks1940 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - "Excursion Fares East from California"1947 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Commission on Tours for Ticket Agentsn.d. (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Destination pamphlets, 1899 - ca. 1951, Series 5
  - Pacific Coast, 1905 - ca. 1951, n.d., Subseries 5.1
    - Carefree Vacations and five small "vacation" pampletsn.d. (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - "Scenic Washington"1904 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - " A Trip to the Orient"1904 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - "Outings at Lake Chelan"1905 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - "Camera Journey to Lewis and Clark"1905 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - "To the Scenic Northwest"1909 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - "Fishing the Skykomish"[1909?] (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - "Washington"1922 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - "To the Evergreen Pacific Northwest and California"1934 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - "Vacation Preview--Pacific Coast"[1930s ?] (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - "Great Northern Takes You to the Great Pacific Coast"[1951?] (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - "The Scenic Northwest"n.d. (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - "Via American Routes to Alaska"n.d. (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - "From California Through Adventure Land"n.d. (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - "Oregon for the Farmer"n.d. (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - "Three Great Dams"n.d. (Box 2, Folder 59)
      Fort Peck Dam, Grand Cooulee Dam, Bonneville Dam
  - Mountain and Midwest, 1899 - 1948, n.d., Subseries 5.2
    - "A New Railway, Great Northern"[1899 ?] (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - "Lake McDonald" [1890s ?] (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - "A Summer Playground" [1904 ?] (Box 2, Folder 62)
      Lake Park Region of Minnesota
    - "Sidelights on the Lake McDonald Country"[1905 ?] (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - "Opening Indian Reservations, Standing Rock and Cheyenne River"1909, Oct. (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - "Opening Indian Reservations, Flathead, Couer d'Alene, Spokane"1909, Jul. and Aug. (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - "Glacier National Park"1909 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - "Glacier National Park"1919 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - "The Call of the Mountains"1924 (Box 2, Folder 68)
      Glacier National Park
    - "The Call of the Mountains"[1927 ?] (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - "Great Northern Vacations"[ 1920s ?] (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - "We Cordially Invite You to Glacier National Park"[1920s ?] (Box 2, Folder 71)
      Great Northern Railway
    - "Glacier National Park"[1920s ?] (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - "Glacier National Park and Waterton Lakes"[1920s ?] (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - "Glacier National Park and Yellowstone National Park"[1920s ?] (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - "Montana"[1920s ?] (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Glacier Park Hotel (postcard)1931 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - "Vacation Tours -- Century of Progress," Chicago's World's Fair1933 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - "Visit the Exposition by Rail--Century of Progress"1933, Feb. (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - "The Empire Builder and Glacier National Park1933 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - "Glacier National Park"1934 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - "Glacier National Park Season"1935 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - "Trail Riding in Glacier National Park"1935 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - "62nd Imperial Council Session" (Shriners)1936, Jul. (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - "Easy Motor Tours Throough Glacier National Park"1936 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - "Rocky Mountain Saddle Trips"(1937 ?) (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - "Glacier National Park (Waterton Lakes)"1938 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - "Glacier National Park, A Paradise for Hikers"1938 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - "Vacations in the Land of the Shining Mountains"1939 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - "Announcing the 27th Season--Glacier National Park"(1930s ?) (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Five small pamphlets and carefree vacations--Glacier National Park[1930s ?] (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - "Glacier National Park and Lake Louise"[1930s ?] (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - "Trail Riding in the Rockies"[1930s ?] (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - "Dude Ranching in the Rockies"[1930s ?] (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - "Glacier National Park, Waterton Lakes"[1930s ?] (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - "Hiking in Glorious Glacier Park"1940 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - "Glorious Glacier Park"1940 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - "Dude Ranch Vacations"[1941 ?] (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - "Glorious Glacier Park"1942 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Glacier National Park and New Logan Pass Detour[1940s ?] (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - "Enchanting Glacier National Park"[1948 ?] (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Chicago Railroad Fair1948 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - East, ca. 1920 - 1946, Subseries 5.3
    - "Straight East"[1920s ?] (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - "Travel East Through Adventure Land" (General)1934 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - "Travel East Through Adventure Land" (California edition)1935 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - "Travel East Through Adventure Land" (Northwest edition), 1935 (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - "Great Cities of the East"1935 (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - "East on the Empire Builder"[1939 ?] (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - "East on the Empire Builder"[1940s ?] (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - "Historic Lake George"1946 (Box 2, Folder 109)
- Advertising reprints and tearsheets, 1933 - 1944, Series 6
  - "Pack Up Your Troubles"1933 (Box 2, Folder 110)
    Tear sheet from The Chicagoan
  - "Ground Crews"1944 (Box 2, Folder 111)
    Teear sheet from Business Week
  - "Rolling Through the Rockies"[1940s ?] (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - "Power"[1940s] (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - "An Old Hand in the Pacific Trade"[1940s ?] (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - "Modern China"[1940s ?] (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - "The New Empire Builder"[1940s ?] (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - "The New Empire Builder"[1940s ?] (Box 2, Folder 117)
- Timetables, 1895 - 1947, Series 7
  - "Time Tables" (Pacific Coast and Midwest)1895, Aug., Sep., and Nov. (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - "Time Tables," (Pacific Coast and Midwest)1895, Dec. 15 (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - "Time Tables, " (Pacific Coast and Midwest)1896, Jun. (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - "New Time"1899 (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - "Eastern Minnesota (the Bee Line)"1899, Nov. (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - "Route of the Fast Mail"1902, Nov. (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - " Time Tables,"1904, Sep. (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - "Time Tables"1904, Oct. (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - "Great Northern Railway"!905, Feb. (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - "Time Tables" 1905, Mar. (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - "Time Tables"1905, Apr. (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - "Time Tables"1905, May (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - Time Tables"1905, Jul. (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - "Time Tables"1905, Oct. (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - "Time Tables"1906, Apr. (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - "Route of the Oriental Limited"1906, Oct. (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - "Local Time Tables"1906, Oct. (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - "Route of the Oriental Limited"1907, Jan. (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - "Route of the Oriental Limited"1907, Mar. (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - "Route of the Oriental Limited"1907, Jun. (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - "Route of the Oriental Limited"1909, Mar. (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - "Route of the Oriental Limited"1909, Jun. (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - "Route of the Oriental Limited"1909, Aug. (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - "Route of the Oriental Limited"1909, Sep. (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - "Route of the Oriental Limited"1909, Nov. (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - "Route of the Oriental Limited"1910, Feb. (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - "Route of the Oriental Limited"1910, Apr. (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - "Route of the Oriental Limited"1910, Jun. (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - "Route of the Oriental Limited"1910, Aug. (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - "Route of the Oriental Limited"1910, Oct. (Box 3, Folder 147)
  - "Route of the Oriental Limited"1910, Dec. (Box 3, Folder 148)
  - "Route of the Oriental Limited"1911, Jun. (Box 3, Folder 149)
  - "Time Tables, Empire Builder"1940, May (Box 3, Folder 150)
  - "The Streamlined Empire Builder"1947, Feb. (Box 3, Folder 151)
- Miscellaneous, 1931 - 1948, Series 8
  - "Summer Tours" 1931 - 1932 (Box 3, Folder 152)
    Peck Judah Travel Bureau
  - "By Truck Across America" 1956, Feb. (Box 3, Folder 153)
    American Magazine
  - Postcard reservation order1948, Apr. (Box 3, Folder 154)
    Arthur L. Scott, Assenger Agent; San Francisco, California; Great Northern Railway